hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this task automation course today we
are going to talk about how you can
create a template and stamps in the last
video i showed you how you can create a
test case template now it's basically
the next step is to instantiate that
particular template so that different
instances of test cases could be created
automatically
or dynamically right
so test cases can be dynamically
generated from a test case template by
creating a template instance
or in other words it is also called
instantiate right
the test case template instance must be
linked to a data source
that data source could be a test design
sheet or it could be excel sheet and
this will be used for generating the
test cases
now the steps to uh generate or
instantiate a template as basically what
we have discussed earlier convert your
test case
which is to be instantiated into a
template
link the test sheet with the test case
template by dragging and dropping the
test design sheet to the test case
template
link the tester values with the
attribute values of the test sheet now
this will be done when you drag and drop
or link the design sheet with the
template
but if some values are not present you
can specifically do that by using the
excel parameter right which we have
already seen
now the last step is to select the
option instantiate or create template
instance from the test case template
options okay which we are going to see
now
are in tosca
so there are two ways to create an
instance of the template from the test
custom that options right
so one way is
select the test case template
go to the test cases section
and there is an option for instantiate
right there are also shortcuts which you
can use
the other option is right click and
there you will find an option
right if you click on the extra options
you will see there is
an option called create template
instance right it's both are the same
things
but there are different ways of doing it
okay
so just click on this um
right on the test case template
and click on instantiate now that will
throw you a dialog saying start
instantiation now
click on yes
and that should now create a template
instance for your test case template
right
now this
will also contain different test cases
so
this is your template and these are your
test cases new test cases which are now
generated automatically or dynamically
from the template
since we had only two instances in our
test design sheet which is our data
source only two test cases were
generated but you have more instances it
will generate any number of test pieces
right so that's the power of tosca which
gives you this reusable option
where you can
have your design sheet to be linked with
your template and then you can
generate any number of test cases right
and that also with different values
okay
now you can see here um
if you see it is using a standard user
and the password here right
for login user for
and the
all the remaining steps are same here
but it is not violating an error here
because i left it empty right
for that particular attribute
now in the second test case you will see
we are using a different username which
is locked out user
and there is a error message which needs
to be verified so you can see these are
two different combinations of test cases
which were generated out of the same
template but the values were different
in our test design sheet which is our
source of data right
and that is how it is driving or
generating this test cases
so it becomes very easy to generate
different test cases with different test
data right once you have
your test design sheet ready and your
template ready
now another scenario here could be
once you
instantiate your template
um scenario would come where you need to
change something in your test case
design or you want to change something
in your template right
so for example uh here my password is an
um data type string but let's make it
password so that it's hidden
right
so um once i do this uh there is a
change in my template right
but uh it is it will not directly impact
my test cases they are not going to
change directly right because those are
already generated
now you will think um you need to
manually go and change that here but
that's not the case
there is an option for that as well in
tosca
so go to your template instance right
click and you will see an option
reinstantiate instance right
so as soon as you make some change in
your template or test design sheet you
will see this option
and
that option will also be present on the
top menu okay
so just click on this and then it is
going to reinstantiate
um your test cases
and you should be able to see the change
which you did in your template right
so now you see the password
as must right because the data type has
changed from string to password
so once you instantiate your test cases
or your test template it
uh it is not necessary that you cannot
make changes you can still make changes
to your test design sheet or
your a test case template and apply
those
same changes across all the test cases
so now you can see how powerful tosca is
the reusability features which tosca
provides you with
through which once
there are efforts in designing your test
case design sheet
and your template but once that is done
you can generate any number of test
cases with different test data
combinations
you